Bauchwitz, Kurt (Roy C. Bates); Papers ger011
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Miscellaneous Materials, 1940-1977; 5; 73 file folders
  - Barbara Bates Materials, 1948-1977; 5.2; 23 file folders
    - Notes concerning the posthumous publication of the writings of Roy C. Bates, Undated; 5.2.4 (Box 17 (5-Miscellaneous Materials), Folder 31-41)
      - "Ego und Echo. Lyrik des 'Lebendigen'". Notes concerning projected volume of Bates' poetry, edited by Harry Zohn (Box 17 (5.2.4-Notes concerning the posthumous publication of the), Folder 32)
        Autograph 85p.
      - "Der Zitronenbaum". Notes concerning poems to be included in projected volume, co-edited by Barbara Bates, Mireille Abeille and Rolf v. Ehrenfels, to be published by Berkau (Box 17 (5.2.4-Notes concerning the posthumous publication of the), Folder 33)
        Autograph ca. 200p.
      - "Der Zitronenbaum". Notes concerning classification of poems by subject matter (Box 17 (5.2.4-Notes concerning the posthumous publication of the), Folder 34)
        Autograph 93p.
      - "Der Zitronenbaum". Notes concerning the proofreading of poem texts to be included in the volume; includes numerous references to exchanges with Mireille Abeille v. Ehrenfels (Box 17 (5.2.4-Notes concerning the posthumous publication of the), Folder 35)
      - Secondary literature. Notes, criticisms, concerning articles written about Roy C. Bates, including those by Wayne Wonderly and Thomas Hansen (Box 17 (5.2.4-Notes concerning the posthumous publication of the), Folder 36)
        Autograph 24p.
      - Translation. Notes concerning translation of poems from Der Lebendige (Box 17 (5.2.4-Notes concerning the posthumous publication of the), Folder 37)
        Arranged in loose alphabetical order, with corresponding pages from the volume indicated.
      - Translation. Notes concerning translation of poems from the "Gedichte", "Abzieh-Bilderbuch" and "Tokyo poems" collections (Box 17 (5.2.4-Notes concerning the posthumous publication of the), Folder 38)
        Arranged alphabetically by title of poem. Autograph circa 170p.
      - Translation. Notes concerning the translation of epigrams from the "Versepigramme I and II" collections (Box 17 (5.2.4-Notes concerning the posthumous publication of the), Folder 39)
        Autograph 142p.
      - Translation. Notes concerning a translation of the article by U.R. v. Ehrenfels on Roy C. Bates (Box 17 (5.2.4-Notes concerning the posthumous publication of the), Folder 40)
        Autograph 12p.
      - Typing, proofreading, 1977 (Box 17 (5.2.4-Notes concerning the posthumous publication of the), Folder 41)
        Notes concerning manuscript preparation. Autograph and Typescript ca. 55p.; Drafts of 2 letters to Ursula Dafeldecker (typist).
- Oversize Materials, 6
  Oversize materials include: Bates' diplomas from Columbia University, New York University, 2 paintings (presumably gifts), and an audio tape of the memorial service for Roy C. Bates.
  - 1. Diploma. Columbia University School of Library Science, 1943 (Box 18 (6-Oversize Materials))
  - 2. Diploma. New York University, School of Law, 1956 (Box 18 (6-Oversize Materials))
  - 3. Painting, signed, Undated (Box 18 (6-Oversize Materials))
  - 4. Painting, entitled "The fence", signed Yoanna, Undated (Box 18 (6-Oversize Materials))
  - 5. Audio tape. Memorial service for Roy C. Bates, 1974 September (Box 18 (6-Oversize Materials))